Profile

Over twenty years experience in the technology industry. Over seventeen years experience designing and building complex systems. Expert in Linux, scripting, automation, and cloud infrastructure. Created automation system using AWS services. Developed two applications for macOS.

Experience

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER; TARGETSMART - 2016-CURRENT

Rearchitected cloud infrastructure with CloudFormation and CodeDeploy for increased security, scaleability, and management. Developed a cloud-native, encrypted secret storage and retrieval service in Python. Deployed a customized Go binary that provided secure OAUTH2 proxy for distributed access to static sites. Led the infrastructure efforts and cloud migration projects.

SYSTEMS AUTOMATION ENGINEER; CHIROTOUCH - 2014-2016

Rebuilt the QA, Staging, and Production environments with AWS CloudFormation and CodeDeploy services, the system can rebuild an environment from scratch in approximately fifteen to twenty minutes. Managed deployment and building of Docker containers for several Ruby on Rails and Java applications. Rearchitected cloud infrastructure for security and efficiency.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR; CDS GLOBAL - 2007-2014

Responsible for designing and maintaining the Linux and AIX high-availability infrastructure for several high demand e-commerce web sites. Worked with a team to build the virtual infrastructure comprised of thirty physical servers and over 160 virtual servers. Designed, installed and maintained several systems including Puppet, Nagios, and Postfix.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR; UNITED STATES NAVY - 1995-2006

Active duty in the U.S. Navy for eleven years, leaving the service with an honorable discharge as a first class petty officer, IT1(SW). Supervised and trained four teams of personnel (3-5 people per team) responsible for the operation and maintenance of satellite communication equipment of JMF St. Mawgan. Designed and managed the creation of a Network Operations Center that centralized network security and information assurance functions. Designed a unified network infrastructure to support five dispersed Internet cafes on the base.

Skills

19 Years - Linux and Unix Administration

19 Years - Shell Scripting

10 Years - Version Control Systems (Git, Mercurial, Subversion)

9 Years - Leadership and Supervision

9 Years - System Automation

7 Years - AWS, Building fully automated infrastructure

3+ Years - Network Security Administration

3+ Years - Programming in Python

3 Years - Cocoa/Objective-C Mac OS X Development

20+ Years - Accepting and Overcoming the Hardest Problems

Education

Iowa State University - Master of Science, Human Computer Interaction, 2012

University of Maryland University College - Bachelor of Science, Information Systems Management, 2008

Several technical classes, including TCP/IP, Solaris Administration, Advanced Solaris Administration, and several years of self-directed technical education.